AYAZ ALIYEV

DATA SCIENTIST

Cell phone: (0) 7305328601 e-mail: ayazliyev@gmail.com

I have pursued academic training in the field of management and have also gained practical experience through an internship in finance and management at the largest industrial company in Azerbaijan. Furthermore, I have worked as an education analyst and consultant for half a year. Currently, I am pursuing studies in data science and have developed a specialized skillset in data management and analysis through the completion of various projects.

Industry Experience, Specialties, Skills, Core Competencies:

Programming Skills: Python, R, Oracle SQL, IBM SPSS, KNIME. Data Wrangling: Ability to clean, transform, and manipulate data using tools such as Pandas, and NumPy. Statistical Modeling: Experience with statistical models such as regression, clustering, decision trees, and machine learning algorithms. Data Visualization: Ability to communicate insights and results through visualizations using tools such as Tableau, PowerBI, and Matplotlib. Big Data Technologies: Knowledge of distributed computing frameworks such as Spark. Communication Skills, Problem-Solving. Data Ethics: Knowledge of data ethics and privacy laws to ensure ethical and responsible use of data.

EXPERIENCE

Go and Study

Baku, Azerbaijan

https://goandstudy.az/ - "Go and Study" is a licensed professional education centre that specializes in overseas education services. It is headquartered in the capital of Azerbaijan Baku city - the business hub of the country, as well as we have offices in Ganja and Istanbul. Moreover, we are in official cooperation with local agencies from CIS, Middle and Far East, Africa and North American countries.

10.03.2022 - 26.09.2022 - Education analyst and consultant

Main responsibilities – Conducting research and analysis: This includes analyzing student performance, tracking trends, and identifying areas for improvement and developing recommendations based on the analysis.

- Collaborating with educators and administrators: Work closely with educators and administrators to
 implement recommended changes and ensure that they are effective. This may involve providing training,
 conducting workshops, or offering other forms of support.
- Communicating with stakeholders: Communicate findings and recommendations to a range of stakeholders, including educators, administrators, and the company's leadership team.

Baku Steel Company

Baku, Azerbaijan

<u>https://www.bakusteel.com/en/</u> – Baku Steel Company, the largest metallurgical company in the Caucasus, having its own place in the economy of the country. Continuously developing its export policy, the Company exports its products to Russia, Georgia and other countries, and cooperates with world-renowned companies, such as Siemens VAI, Demora, Danieli, Vezzani, Air Liquide, CVS and others in order to improve its production and be abreast of the times.

16.02.2022 - 31.05.2022 - Finance and Management Intern

Main responsibilities – Assisting with financial analysis: Responsible for conducting financial analysis to help the company make informed decisions about investments, expenses, and revenue. Supporting accounting and financial reporting: Assist with tasks such as bookkeeping, reconciling accounts, and preparing financial statements.

- Assisting with management tasks: Support management tasks such as tracking project progress, preparing reports, and coordinating with other departments.
- Conducting research: Conducting research on various topics related to the company's operations, such as market trends, industry regulations, or competitor analysis.
- Participating in team meetings: Meetings with other team members to discuss progress on projects, share ideas, and receive feedback.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD

Sheffield, UK

Baku, Azerbaijan

26.09.2022 - Present MSc Data Science

- Current GPA: 71 out of 100
- Expected to be graduated with distinction.

AZERBAIJAN STATE ECONOMIC UNIVERSITY

16.09.2018 – 15.07.2022 **BSc Management**

• Graduated with honours, GPA: 95 out of 100.

ADDITIONAL

- Language Skills: Azerbaijani (native), Turkish (bilingual proficiency), and English (fluent).
- Volunteer Activities: UEFA, FORMULA1.